(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T18:09:52.723261",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
バンダイ・バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
ホロライブEXPO 2025の特設ブースで展示中の商品をご紹介！
introducing the products on display at the Hololive EXPO 2025 special booth!
ホロライブEXPO 2025限定の
Exclusive to Hololive EXPO 2025,
一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
a special Ichiban Kuji photo booth is also open!
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、
Touch the monitor to flip the lottery ticket,
出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます！
and you can take a picture with the design that appears!
その歌声を響かせて
Let your singing voice echo,
夢の続きを探そう
let's search for the continuation of our dreams.
あの感動をもう一度...
That emotion once again...
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
Furyu's Hololive prizes are rolling out across amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
Starting in April, Hugging Figures will also make their debut!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service during your Taiwan trip.
新商品まもなく登場！
New products coming soon!
JOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
Let's sing on JOYSOUND X1!
曲数No.1
No. 1 in song selection
AIが採点 絶賛
Highly praised AI scoring
カラオケ最高！最高！
Karaoke is the best! The best!
歌いたい曲があるって最高
Having songs you want to sing is the best!
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
ホロライブEXPO 2025の会場にある特設ブースで、
at the special booth in the hololive EXPO 2025 venue,
展示中の商品をご紹介！
introducing the products on display!
ホロライブEXPO 2025限定の一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
Hololive EXPO 2025 limited Ichiban Kuji special photo booth is also available!
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます！
Touch the monitor to flip through lottery tickets and take photos with the design that appears!
hololive 5th fes. で歌われた The Last Frontier からなんと！
And from hololive 5th fes., featuring songs from "The Last Frontier"!
フィギュア化決定！
Scale figure adaptation decided!
あの感動をもう一度… 旅立つ歌を
Experience that emotion once more... a song of departure.
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
FuRyu's "hololive" prizes are rolling out sequentially across amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
Starting in April, new hanging figures will also appear!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service during your trip to Taiwan.
新商品まもなく登場！
New products coming soon!
JOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
Let's sing with JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 オンライン！
JOYSOUND X1 Online!
JOYSOUND X1 曲数No.1！
JOYSOUND X1 has the No. 1 song library!
AIが採点 絶賛！カラオケが最高！最高！
AI scoring is acclaimed! Karaoke is the best, the best!
曲数No.1！歌いたい曲があるって最高！
No. 1 in songs! Having the song you want to sing is the best!
超特大ぬいぐるみブランド「どきゅーと」から商品化決定！
Productization decided from the super extra-large plush brand "Doqute"!
約100cmサイズぬいぐるみ！
Approx. 100cm sized plush!
2025年夏 受注開始予定
Pre-orders scheduled to start in summer 2025!
タイトブースにてサンプル展示中！
Sample on display at the Taito booth!
グルーヴコースター最新作に白上フブキと
Shirakami Fubuki joins the latest Groove Coaster...
さくらみこがキャラクターボイスで参戦！
and Sakura Miko joins with character voices!
人気曲や私たちが歌う曲も楽しめる！
Enjoy popular songs and songs sung by us!
私たちがグルーヴワールドをナビゲートするよ！
We will navigate you through Groove World!
コラボイベント実施中！
Collaboration event underway!
ゲームのオアシスに飛び込め！
Dive into the gaming oasis!
harmony 重ねた 言葉 届け
harmony — layered words, reach out
たどたどしく 描いては
clumsily drawing our dreams
ぎこちない と 笑ってた
laughing at how awkward they seemed
未来予想 あの日の続きを 見よう
let’s continue the story we envisioned that day
手と手 繋いで 風も着こなして
hand in hand, embracing the wind
扉 を 叩いて 連れ て きて よ
knock on doors — we’ll go along
どんな こと も きっと
no matter what comes our way
一緒 なら 叶え て いける
if we’re together, we can make it happen
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
鳴りやまない 希望のベル ほら
the bell of hope keeps ringing — listen
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
聞こえてる歌 ah
can you hear this song? ah …
harmony 重ねた言葉
harmony — layered words
鮮やかな日々の向こう
beyond the vivid days ahead
ずっと君と彩るよ ストーリー
always with you, we’ll color this story
ハートに結んだ夢が
the dreams tied to our hearts
空へ駆け てゆく
race toward the sky
キラメキ に乗せて
carried on shimmering light —
あなたへ届け
let them reach you
メロディー どこまでも ！
this melody — endlessly !
何気ない こと 思い出す
recalling the little things
一人 じゃ ない って 深呼吸
taking a deep breath, knowing I’m not alone
未体験 楽しむ 魔法 の 言葉
embracing the unknown — that’s the magic of words
一息 ついて ふと 振り返っ て
pausing for a moment, looking back
また 君 を 知っ て そのたびに
learning more about you each time
ちょっと 勇気 出し て
and with just a bit of courage
明日 へ 飛び込ん で いける
I can dive into tomorrow
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
降り積もる 道しるべ は まだ
the path ahead is still being laid
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
覚えてる 歌 ah
yet I remember this song, ah …
harmony 手を伸ばしたら
harmony — when I reach out
足跡に 虹 が かかる
a rainbow forms over our footprints
きっと 晴れる 口ずさむ ステージ
the sky will surely clear, humming on this stage
ハート に 記し た 場所 へ
guided by the marks on my heart
運ぶ 約束 を
a promise carries me forward
輝き に 乗せ て
riding on its radiance
世界 へ 響け
let it echo through the world —
メロディー いつまでも ！
this melody, forever !
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
君と踏み出したあの 一歩 あの瞬間が
that first step we took together, that very moment
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
宝物だって 胸を張る 今
is now a treasure I hold with pride
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
歩いて話してはしゃいで笑顔でゆくんだ
walking, talking, playing, smiling — moving forward
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
色褪せないまま
without fading away
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
混ざり合う僕らの声ほら
our voices blend together — listen
【 la - la - la - la 】
[ la - la - la - la ]
聞こえてる歌 ah
can you hear this song? ah …
harmony 重ねた言葉
harmony — layered words
鮮やかな日々の向こう
beyond the vivid days ahead
ずっと君と彩るよ ストーリー
always with you, we’ll color this story
ハートに結んだ夢が
the dreams tied to our hearts
空へ駆け てゆく
race toward the sky
キラメキ に乗せて
carried on shimmering light —
あなたへ届け
let them reach you
世界へ響け
let them echo through the world
愛を込めて
with love
メロディー どこまでも ！
this melody — endlessly !
ハレ ハレ ハレ 輝くんだよ
Shine, shine, shine, it's shining bright!
呼び合う声を合図に
Taking our calling voices as the signal,
ハレ ハレ ハレ 探しに行く
Shine, shine, shine, we're going to search,
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start over,
ありがと続いた
Thank you for continuing,
ただ 始まりたくって走った
I just wanted it to begin, so I ran!
遠く 暗がり見守った
Guarding the distant darkness,
それは 眩しすぎた名前
That name was far too dazzling.
それは 優しすぎた思い出
Those memories were far too gentle.
もっと 近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get even closer,
想いだけ結び合った
Only our feelings were intertwined.
ハレ ハレ ハレ 輝くんだよ
Shine, shine, shine, it's shining bright!
悔しさも愛しさも全部連れて
Taking all our frustration and affection with us,
おいで 果てせぬ夢 跳ね 飛び立てるさ
Come on, endless dreams, bound and take flight!
ささやかな祈りばかり
Just simple, quiet prayers,
終わりなき軌跡
An endless track.
君を見つけたこと
Finding you,
胸を張れるよ ここから
I can hold my head high, right from here.
これから 甘くない
From here on, it won't be easy,
ハレ ハレ ハレ
Shine, shine, shine!
まだ 足りない予感を
Feelings that are still not enough,
歌を 恥ずかしさなんてないよ
Singing without any embarrassment.
誰も 解けないいまいましさに
In a frustration nobody can solve,
いつか また逢えますように
Hoping we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった
It all started from the zero of that day,
そう 数え切れない鼓動は 数えるようなもんじゃないさ
Yes, countless heartbeats aren't something to just count.
ほら 今 僕らを一つにしよう
Look, now let's make us all one!
ハレ ハレ ハレ
Shine, shine, shine,
美しんだよ
It's so beautiful!
許し合える切なさは
Forgiving each other's painful nights,
夜は諦めず
Without giving up on the night,
雨 ハレ ハレ
Rain, shine, shine,
また絶えない空
The sky that never stops clearing,
新しい道とは 君と
A new path is walking together with you.
harmony 重ねた 言葉 届け
Harmony, layered words, reach out
たどたどしく 描いては
Clumsily drawing...
ぎこちないと笑ってた
Laughing at how awkward we seemed
未来予想 あの日の続きを見よう
Let's see the continuation of that day's future
おかえりって叫ぶよ
I'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないから
Because it's not something to be taken for granted
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shine bright!
暗闇を満たすドア
The door that fills the darkness
君だ 僕だ
It's you, it's me
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shine bright!
増やした想いも愛おしさも連れて
Bringing along the increased feelings and tenderness
おいで 駆け抜け 跳ね 飛び越えてるさ
Come on, running through, leaping and jumping over
鮮やかな今を二人 終わりなきキズナ
The two of us in these vivid days, an endless bond
君と飛び込んでいく
Diving in with you
素敵な姿こそさ
That wonderful figure
ここから これから
From here, from now on
あなたのトライ
Your try
パレ パレ パレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shine bright!
誰にも渡さない 僕だけのプリンセス
I won't give you to anyone, my princess
大好きになればいいんじゃない？
Wouldn't it be great if you loved me?
なんとかできないかな
Can't we do something about this?
ノリのいい相槌じゃまだな
Upbeat nodding isn't enough yet
プレート必勝絶対
Absolute victory plate
とわとは違うな なんたって競争
It's different from forever, after all it's a competition
逃げ道はそうゆうの
Escape routes like that...
ガンダム 進め 気持ちはジモティ
Go forward, Gundam, feelings are like locals
その子に負けないって 敵殴ってけらしい
I won't lose to that girl, beating enemies fiercely
横取りめ 横取りか
Stealing it away? Taking it?
滅ぼしてやります ああ！
I'll destroy you, ah!
言わなきゃ手は分かってる
If I don't say it, you understand
ってものない
There's no such thing
とてもない とてもない
No way, no way
やめにしましょう 抜け出せない まいまいまいまい
Let's call it quits, we can't escape
聞きたくない言い訳ばかり
Just excuses I don't want to hear
じだんだのYouTuber だんだんだん
A foot-stamping YouTuber, dan-dan-dan
初めはなりなりなりの
At first, it was somewhat...
その一歩が 好きなのよ
That first step is what I love
よそ見しないで
Don't look away
モニッケタシタイのわ 私の方
The one who wants to get close is me
少しは反省よ ここは満点さ言い訳バル
Reflect a bit, this is a perfect score
なんだけティ 手放せない やりきっちゃいなさい
What is this? You can't let go, just do it!
手頃な一刀 両断じゃやりすぎちゃえ！
An affordable single sword slash might be going too far!
大体がいい？ もう大抵がいい？
Is general good? Is most of it good?
興味かねから チョーミーかねって
From interest, seasoning...
人波 君さかす ハリケーン 届けきおみ
Crowds, turning upside down, hurricane...
少し白目 むくってボエミ どんなエンジェル
Slightly rolling your eyes... what kind of angel
パワフルキャラクター バイのスト 全身
Powerful character, whole body
愛のあるのみ
Only with love
転んでエネルギー 正面から幕を張り やっちまいなさい
Stumbling into energy, just do it!
疲れちゃった 一休み なんとかね
Got tired, a short rest, somehow
やってよね 明日の技
Do it, tomorrow's technique
まかせて まいまいまいまい
Leave it to me, mai-mai-mai-mai
決められない 言い訳ばに
Can't decide, making excuses
うやむや年中 痛かす とん とん とん とん
Vague all year round, poking ton-ton-ton-ton
二目に間に間に 間違いなしの 楽しい話は
Without mistake, fun stories
とっし まえ 明日 まえ です
Before this year, before tomorrow
あったかい まえ です
Warm before
おんなのぺんちゃい
A girl's...
私 一筋 の 毎分 君 が 好き な の よ
Every minute dedicated to me, I love you
どこへだって 行けばいい
Wherever you go, it's fine
言い訳ない よせしない 冗談じゃない
No excuses, don't hold back, no joking
続けろ まいまいまいまい
Keep going, mai-mai-mai-mai
聞きたくない 言い訳ばに
Don't want to hear excuses
じだんだのYouTuber だんだんだん
A foot-stamping YouTuber, dan-dan-dan
初めはだんだん まだ まだ の 一言
At first, gradually, still words of...
やかまししないで
Don't be so noisy!
もう逃げ出しちゃいたい
I already want to run away,
けどやるしかない
but I have no choice but to do it.
予想も千変万化の本能
Even instinct changes a thousand ways,
ワン・テン・サイ・言い訳・バニー
one, ten, sai, excuse bunny!
逃げ出して言い訳バニー
Running away, excuse bunny!
探偵気取ってるし！
Acting like a detective!
行くわよ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, go!
無罪！無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty!
美少女無罪マリーン！
Cute girl not guilty, Marine!
マリーン！マリーン！
Marine! Marine!
マリーンは無罪！
Marine is not guilty!
酔っぱキラキラ そうクラクラ
Drunk sparkling, so dizzy,
ねぇ聞いてよ ねぇ
hey, listen to me, hey.
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
You say age doesn't matter,
そういうめんどいのも含めて愛してくれるって
and that you love all those troublesome things too.
ねぇねぇ聞いてよ ねぇ
Hey, hey, listen to me, hey.
聞いてない？ ふーん、そう言うこと言うんだ
You're not listening? Hmph, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
By the way, the cute girl not guilty rule applies here!
任せて お・ほ・ほ で裁かれび！
Leave it to me! Tried with o-ho-ho!
秘密の素顔は君にだけ
My secret true face is only for you,
お見せしちゃうから
so I'll show it to you.
出航！
Set sail!
遊べ出せよ！
Have fun and let loose!
落とし所はここよ
The compromise is right here,
港じゃないんだから
since it's not a port after all.
星屑の願いは
Stardust wishes
ちゃんと届いてね
will reach you properly, right?
宝の島に髭を生やし 気分上々出航！
Grow a beard on Treasure Island, high spirits, set sail!
誘導せいぎ 美少女無罪！
Guiding justice, cute girl not guilty!
君のいちばんを目指してよ空を
Aim for your number one in the sky!
今度は自信ないけど頑張っちゃっほい！
This time I'm not confident, but I'll do my best!
ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅるん
Gyurun, gyurun, gyurun,
恋する気持ちチューニング
tuning feelings of love.
天使になっちゃおは 大人のお時間
Let's become angels, adult time.
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzy,
ドキドキして るーし！
heart pounding, oops!
まだ早い？
Still too early?
食べたてでタップリの服着たら
If you wear a stuffed outfit right after eating,
そんなことないって
you say that's not true.
魔法少女になってみたい
I want to become a magical girl,
ギリギリ誘拐？
barely a kidnapping?
姫の七変化のピュアな意気込み
The princess's pure enthusiasm in seven transformations,
結局キミももっと若い子
in the end, you prefer younger girls too.
なんだってするから見せてライデキミタチ
You'd do anything, so show us, you guys!
やっと言いたかった見てみたい！
I finally wanted to say it, I want to see it!
年頃だから 本気にしちゃう
Because I'm at that age, I'll take it seriously.
ルシのさかさま 一緒に行こう！
Luci's upside-down, let's go together!
出航！
Set sail!
ハートにジャム 美少女無罪！
Jam in the heart, cute girl not guilty!
俺れ同士の面倒くさいを乗っ取り
Hijacking our mutual troubles,
ちょっぴり構ってくれる 気分好き好き
pay a little attention to me, feeling love-love.
ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅるん 優しくしてね呪う7歳
Gyurun, be gentle, cursing 7-year-old.
突っ込んでけ 現実をお楽しみに
Dive into reality, look forward to it.
やっぱキラキラ
Still sparkling,
もっとクラクラ
even more dizzy,
ドキドキして るーし！
heart pounding, oops!
まだ早い？ お許しくだちゃい！
Still too early? Please forgive me!
このマリーンの 魅力・魔力 ふっ飛ばせくー！
This Marine's charm and magic, blow them away!
海のオンナだ！
A woman of the sea!
そんなさないで 捕まえていて
Don't be like that, catch and hold on.
絶対の色のさ 見せてあげるから
I'll show you the absolute color.
出航！
Set sail!
誘導せいぎ 美少女無罪！
Guiding justice, cute girl not guilty!
君のいちばんを目指してよ空を
Aim for your number one in the sky!
ジョークも大好きだけど真剣よ
I love jokes too, but I'm serious.
ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅるん 恋する気持ちチューニング
Gyurun, tuning feelings of love.
優しくしてね 呪う7歳
Be gentle, cursing 7-year-old.
天使になっちゃおは 大人のお時間
Let's become angels, adult time.
時々して るーし！
From time to time, oops!
まだ早い？
Still too early?
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Cute girl not guilty!
マリーン！マリーン！マリーンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzy.
マリーンじゃない！マリーン絶叫だ！
Not Marine! Marine screams!
Come on hurry! 楽しんだもん勝ち！
Come on hurry! Whoever enjoys it wins!
盛り上がっていくぞ！ Let's shoot it down!
Let's get hyped! Let's shoot it down!
See the moon from so far away, I reach out my hands, up high
All the shackles on me won't change all the thoughts inside my mind
I won't be quiet, when they say be obedient
I have to make my choices for me, and go the uncharted way
They can't tell me how to live
Baby, how’s your life?
Baby, how's your life?
Are you living free?
Let’s forget everything
Let's forget everything
And have some fun chu chu chu
Here we roll dice,
here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Baby, baby
there’s no need to think twice.
there's no need to think twice.
Dari wari woah
Make it your night, make it your fight,
make it your spotlight
And rule your life!
5 4 3 2 1 play dice!
So the space went bang
And we were all born
The order we knew, ripped and torn
But we have no time to complain
'Cause life is short, can't do it over again
If we can laugh, it doesn't matter where or when
Physics don't play the dice?
So let trouble stir and rise!
No cage can trap this rat!
Here we roll dice, here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Yell and scream come on now,
don't be too nice, dari wari woah
Follow your heart, pump your fist up,
come and join the club!
Go and scream for you the one who's flying free
For this moment I am truly, really me!
5 4 3 2 1 play dice!
Now here I will recite to you
The only thing that will hold true
Yolo is my ninja way
It's time to put those moves out there on display
Why stress about tomorrow
When you've got today?
Wow, aren't we sick as chu?
Wareware tte egui cute
So rush on to our route
No math can settle this rat!
Here we roll dice, here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Come and venture into my dope dumpsite
Dari wari woah
Time to run and follow our sun,
won't stop till we're done!
Idiots are allowed infinite fun
It's never too late, our journey's just begun!
If you hesitate on what to do,
that's it, game over. You are screwed.
Whether you cry or laugh, chu chu chu
Baby, baby, it's our time! It's our time!
Here we roll dice, here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Baby, baby,
there's no need to think twice.
Dari wari woah
Make it your night, make it your fight,
make it your spotlight
Try your best before giving up!
Whatchu doing bruh? Go and live your life!
5 4 3 2 1 play dice!
Here we roll dice, here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Baby, baby,
there's no need to think twice.
Dari wari woah
Make it your night, make it your fight,
make it your spotlight
Before giving in, go show them your best try!
Here we roll dice, here we cast dice,
here we just play dice!
Baby, baby,
there's no need to think twice.
Dari wari woah
Follow your heart, pump your fist up,
come and join the club!
This is our night, this is our fight,
this is our spotlight!
Before giving in, go show them your best try!
What you're doing? Rat, go round and live your life!
そう さ ずっと 僕らの奇跡が 途切れないように 歌うんだ
So let's make our miracle never fade away
もっと 高く 大きな 声で
With a higher, louder voice!
聞こえてた？ 何かが始まるサイン
Did you hear it? A sign that something's beginning.
集まって気付けば和音を奏でてた
Before we knew it, we were playing a harmony.
夢に見るだけ じゃもう足りない でしょ？
Just dreaming isn't enough anymore, is it?
キミを待っている 世界があるよ
There's a world out there waiting for you.
楽しい予感にほら飛び乗っちゃえばいい
Let's just jump right into this exciting feeling!
ドキメキは止められないから走ろう
We can't stop the excitement, so let's run!
連れていくよ 光の真ん中 夢の先へ
Leading us into the heart of the light, beyond our dreams.
羽ばたける勇気は キミの願い
The courage to spread our wings is your wish.
みんなでつないだ この奇跡が 途切れないように 歌うんだ
This miracle we wove together mustn't fade away!
もっと 高く 大きな 声で
Singing it out with a higher, louder voice!
答えとか理屈に 惑わされても
Even when confused by answers and logic,
彷徨っても戻ってこられる場所があったんだ
We always had a place we could return to.
地図にない道行く 僕らの旅
Our journey takes us down roads not found on any map.
願いだけが道しるべだよ
Only our wishes should guide the way.
夢の色が変わっても変わらないメロディー
Even if the colors of our dreams change, the melody remains the same.
キミのために 僕らのために歌おう
Let's sing for you, let's sing for us!
そうさ きっと 僕らの奇跡は終わらないよ
Yes, surely, our miracles will never end.
涙さえきっかけに変えていこう
Let's even turn our tears into stepping stones.
信じてくれる仲間と一緒に
Together with friends we can trust,
どこへだって飛び出していこう
Let's leap out anywhere!
もっと遠く 空を越えて
Farther across the sky,
未来の僕らに まだ見ぬキミに 伝えたいことたくさんあるんだ
There is still so much we want to tell our future selves, and you whom we haven't met yet!
迎えた今は当たり前なんかじゃない
Welcoming the present isn't just a given.
翼を広げ さあ今飛ぼう
Spread your wings and let's fly right now!
見つめ合って恋をして
Locking glances, falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
completely absorbed in chasing you.
だけどもっと知りたくて メラメラしてる
But I want to know more, burning up inside!
願うほど謎が増え 想うほど熱になる
The more I wish, the more mysteries grow.
だからもっと飛び込むの 未開の世界 ah...
So I'll dive deeper into an uncharted world, ah...
恋とか夢とか 誰でも信じるけれど
Everyone believes in love and dreams,
そこそこ攻めなきゃつまらないよ
but playing it safe is just boring!
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Love at the edge of a forbidden borderline!
難易度Gでも すべて壊してみせる
Even at G-difficulty, I'll break it all down.
キリキリ舞 さらなるGへと 意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
Spinning round to a higher G, consciousness melts, body out of control.
いっちゃうかもね
I might just reach the climax!
ふざけあった友達と 求めあったあの人と
With the friends I messed around with, and the one I desired,
また会える日のために ゲラゲラしてる
I'm laughing loudly for the day we meet again.
光るほど影ができ 燃えるほど灰になる
The brighter the shine, the deeper the shadow.
走るほど見えてくる 危ないライン ah...
The more I run, the closer that dangerous line comes, ah...
自由も平和も 望めば生まれるけれど
Freedom and peace are born if you wish for them,
モタモタしてたら 腐ってしまうよ
but hesitate too long and they'll rot away!
ギリギリ愛 あぶないボーダーレス
Love at the edge, a dangerous borderless world!
非常識だね まだ加速しているよ
It's absurd, and it's still accelerating.
キリキリ舞 限界点なら 塗り替えていい
Spinning round, if this is the limit, we'll rewrite it.
破壊と再生から 私ができる
From destruction and rebirth, I am made.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Love at the edge of a forbidden borderline!
難易度Gでも すべて壊してみせる
Even at G-difficulty, I'll break it all down.
キリキリ舞 さらなるGへと 意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
Spinning round to a higher G, consciousness melts, body out of control.
いっちゃうかもね
I might just reach the climax!
我が儘の マニマニ
At the whim of selfishness,
煌めきに チチンプイプイ
with a magic touch upon the sparkle,
知らんぷり忘れて ダンシング
forget playing dumb and start dancing!
さよならコウモリ レトマ
Goodbye, bats and letoma,
いつかはサファイア 暗黒オーディエンス
someday a sapphire, dark audience.
マグハリ アヴェニュー
Maghari Avenue,
ショータイム アーメン！
showtime, amen!
こんながったってもしょうがないから 修羅場どうしない？
There's no point worrying, how about a scene?
今夜明日も 回れ踊れ 重ねてモイスチャー
Tonight and tomorrow, spin and dance, layering moisture.
今夜明日も回れ踊れ 10億年先もマジスティックでしょ
Spin and dance for ten billion years, majestically!
踊れ！
Dance!
楽しかったな みんなのビビでば
That was so fun! Everyone's Bibideba...
楽しかったー！
It was so fun!
こんばんは～！ステージから来ました！みんな戻ってきてくれてありがとう！
Good evening~! We came from the stage! Thanks for coming back!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ではね、えー自己紹介を、ね、させていただけたらなと。こちらから順番にお願いします。
Now then, let's do our self-introductions. Starting from this side, please.
えじゃあみんな、あのコンサメって言ったら、ねねねって返してください。
So everyone, when I say 'Konsame', please reply with 'Nenene'.
えー！こんにちは、ときのそらです！コンサメー！
Hello, I'm Tokino Sora! Konsamē!
ねねねー！
Nenenē!
ありがとう！では次は、AZKiちゃんこれをぜひしたいと思います！
Thank you! Next, AZKi-chan, please go ahead!
はい！いつものね、自己紹介を言ったらみんな「AZKiのハートを」って言ったら「ゼロゲッサー！」で、お願いします！
Yes! When I give my usual intro and say 'AZKi's heart...', please reply 'Zero gessaa!'
ではいきますよ！右手にはマイク、左手に地図。AZKiのハートを？
Here we go! Mic in my right hand, map in my left. AZKi's heart?
ゼロゲッサー！
Zero gessaa!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、じゃあSuiseiはみんな分かってるよね？もう言わないからね。Suisei行きますよ。
Okay, everyone knows Suisei's, right? I won't even say it. Here we go.
星の数から現れた星街すいせいです！スィちゃんはー？
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei, appearing from the stars! Sui-chan is...?
今日もかわいい！
Cute today too!
バッチリ！バッチリ！バッチリ！ありがとー！はいどうぞ！
Spot on! Spot on! Spot on! Thank you~! Go ahead!
はい、じゃあロボ子もコールズやりたい！ロボ子はもちろん、高性能って言ってくれますよね？
Alright, Roboko wants to do a call too! Ofances... you'll call me high-spec, right?
言うよー！
We will!
ではいきます！ロボ子さんは？
Here we go! Roboko-san is...?
高性能ー！
High-spec!
そういうことだよ！しょうがない、ロボ子間違えちゃった。
That's right! Oh well, Roboko messed up.
じゃあねこち、はいどうそ！
Now Nekochi, please go ahead!
え、じゃあみこちゃんはってみんな分かるよね。エリートだよね。
Ah, everyone knows Miko-chan's, right? She's elite.
あれ、何今の？今のは何？あれ大丈夫かな？みこちゃん大丈夫だよね？
Wait, what was that? What was that just now? Is that okay? Miko-chan is fine, right?
おぴぐぴぐだよ！
Opigupigu!
じゃあいきますよ！にょはろー！
Here we go! Nyoharou!
にょはろー！
Nyoharou!
エリート巫女の愛の桜みこです！みこちゃんはー？
I'm elite miko Sakura Miko! Miko-chan is...?
エリートだー！
Elite!
よかったよかった、ありがとー！エリートだ！ということで、リリータスステージ始まりました！
Phew, thank you! Elite! And with that, Lilith/Reelita's stage has begun!
曲から、サビで、パーンって出る感じだったね。頑張りました！
We started right from the chorus with a bang. We did our best!
いやもう最初からもう飛ばしてるセトリでしたけれども、
Well, that was a setlist that went all out right from the start.
そうそうそうね、
Yeah, exactly.
なんかすごい「よかった、よかった」って
Like, we're seeing all these comments like "That was great!"
コメントも...
and comments...
コメント見えてますね。
We can see the comments.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
配信もありがとう！
Thanks to everyone on stream too!
Thanks for the stream!
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
ということで、
So,
えーっと、ハッシュタグは
um, the hashtag is
「#ホロライブフェスEXPO25_アンダーゲート」で
"#HololiveFesEXPO25_Undergate,"
呟いて、たくさんポストしてください！
please tweet and post a lot!
でさ、うん、みんなでやりたいことが...
So, um, there's something we all wanted to do...
あーそうそうやりたいこと、話しててじゃん
Ah right, we were talking about things we wanted to do...
やりたいことあるって、決めましたよね。
We decided on something we wanted to do, right?
じゃあここは説明が上手なあずきさん
So AZKi-san, who is good at explaining—
えっ、ここ説明が上手なあずきさん？うるさい！
Wait, AZKi-san is good at explaining? Shut up!
本日は0期生が集まったということで、
Since today all 0th gen members have gathered,
みんなにペンライトで協力してほしいことがあります！
there's something we want everyone's help with using penlights!
今からちょっと立ち位置を変えますので、みんなの目の前にいるね、
We're going to change positions a bit now, so everyone, the member right in front of you—
あの0期生のメンバーのカラーにペンライトを変えてください！
please change your penlight to that 0th gen member's color!
これで大体、大体みんな分かるかな？
With this, do you think everyone will understand?
えーっとみんなね、今自分の目の前にいるホロメンのカラーにペンライトを変えてみて！
Um everyone, try changing your penlight to the color of the holomember right in front of you now!
すっごい！え、きみたちできるじゃないか！やれるじゃん、今！
Amazing! Hey, you guys can do it! You can do it now!
すごいね、難しいと思ってたね。めっちゃ綺麗に分かれてる！
That's amazing, we thought it would be hard. They're separated so cleanly!
でさ、じゃあちょっとどのチームが一番声がでかいか...
So, um, let's see which team has the loudest voice...
ここで0期生バトルが始まってしまうんだね。あ、お前ら頑張れよ！
Looks like a 0th gen battle is starting here. Hey you guys, do your best!
じゃあ、どこから行くの？ロボ子さん！
So, where do we start? Roboco-san!
じゃあロボ子さん！ごいしょうぶ？ロボ子チームからいきますか？
Then Roboco-san! A match? Shall we start from Roboco's team?
じゃあみんな、声、1発目から出せるよね？
Alright everyone, you can raise your voices right from the start, right?
すっごい！めちゃんこ声出てるじゃん！すごい！すごい！
Amazing! You guys are raising your voices so much! Amazing!
いいよロボ子さんチーム！次すいちゃんチームね！
Great job Roboco-san's team! Next is Suichan's team!
わかっているよね？ あと、名前が大事よ！
You know, right? Also, the name is important!
じゃあ行くよ、すいちゃんはー！...素晴らしい！声がでかい！
Then here we go, Suichan is—! (...) Wonderful! Loud voices!
え、じゃあエリートじゃないやつにしてみようかな。なんだなんだ？
Eh, then let's try making it something that isn't elite. What is it?
じゃあ、みこおねえって言ったら、誇らしいよ！
Then, if I say "Miko-onee", be proud!
行ってもらうかな？恥ずかしい。いやみこ誇らしいとこ最近見せまくってますから。
Can you go? Embarrassed. No, Miko has been showing off her proud side a lot lately.
じゃあ行くよ！みんな行くよ！みこおねえー！
Then let's go! Everyone go! Miko-onee—!
出てる出てる！すごいついてる！よくできたー！よくできた！
It's coming out! Amazing, it's showing! Well done! Well done!
でわでわ、えっとそらが済んだら、そらちゃん！あーありがとう！
Now then, um, once Sora is done, Sora-chan! Ah thank you!
じゃあ私がさっきコンソメって言ったけど今度はみんなにコンソメって言ってもらおうかな？
So earlier I said "Consomme", but this time I want everyone to say "Consomme"?
いいねいいね！できるよね！行くよ！
Sounds good! You can do it! Here we go!
じゃあ私がコンソメって言ったらコンソメって返してください！
So when I say "Consomme", please return it with "Consomme"!
はい、みんな！コンソメーー！
Alright everyone! Con-som-me—!
すごいすごい！いいよいいよ！素晴らしい！素晴らしい！
Amazing, amazing! That's good! Wonderful! Wonderful!
では最後ですからね、みんなちゃんと声出してくださいね！
Now it's the last one, so everyone make sure to raise your voices!
今日は皆さんどこに来ましたか？いいですか？幕張メッセですよ！
Where did everyone come today? Is that okay? It's Makuhari Messe!
皆さん、幕張メッセをゲースでお願いします！ゲースでお願いします！
Everyone, please give Makuhari Messe with "Gees"! Please with "Gees"!
行きますよ！幕張メッセを！
Here we go! Makuhari Messe—!
ゲース！イエーイ！ありがとう！
Gees! Yay! Thank you!
みんな声がでか、みんなの声でかすぎたねー
Everyone's voices were way too loud!
勝者はいない、引き分け
There are no winners, it's a tie.
仲良しだ、仲良しだ
We're good friends, we're good friends.
戻りまして
Returning to the stage,
いやー、戻ります、戻ります、はい
Yeah, returning, returning, yes.
ということで皆さんに悲しいお知らせがあります
With that said, we have some sad news for everyone.
え、え、やだ、やだ、行きたくない、行きたくない！
Huh? No, I don't want to go!
無料パートはここまで
The free part ends here.
まさか、そこのあなたたちまだチケット買ってないの？
Don't tell me... you guys over there still haven't bought tickets?
早く今から買って、その後は観たいでしょ？観たいでしょ？
Hurry up and buy them now, you want to watch after that, right?
よろしくね、よね？
Right?
こんデミら、こんデミら！出でたら、ちゃりちゃり鳴けならー！
Try coming! If you can, jingle-jangle and make some noise!
では、最後のコメントで締めたいと思います
Now, we'd like to close with final comments.
みんな貼っている、あの、あの言葉、あの言葉！
Everyone's putting up, that, that word, that word!
会場の皆さんも一緒に行ってくださいね
Everyone in the venue, please say it together too.
うん
Yup.
え、ポーズは適当で、ポーズは適当、オッケーオッケーオッケー
Uh, poses are random, just random, okay okay okay.
あのこ、ね、おっけーよ
That girl, right, okay.
せーの
Ready, set,
カラーライズ
Color Rise
ハーモニー！
Harmony!